hi my name is Joe brewer and I read a
lot of books that my friends keep
telling me sound really cool and so I
always recommended that I share some of
what I'm learning from these books and
videos so other people can understand
them too so the book that I want to
share with you today is this one social
physics how good ideas spread the
lessons from a new science by Alex
pentland now Alex puntland as a
professor at MIT and help set up one of
their media labs and he's sometimes
considered to be one of the best data
scientists in the world so what he does
in this book is he explores the question
how can we take all of the data that has
now possible to gather and look at human
interactions as if it was a physical
system and then watch how ideas flow
from one person to another two best
figure out how to increase creativity
and innovation and productivity with an
organization or how to optimize say
certain things that want to that one
might want to design for in a city or in
a society and so the book is really a
great book for exploring this very
question I think it's probably the best
book out there for looking at how to
model social systems entirely using data
driven approaches so one of the things
that pentland does throughout the book
that I find really exciting is he and
his collaborators which is a group of
PhD students over the Syria over the
last 20 years is they have found ways to
gather data from human interactions and
then take that data and then model the
social system as if it was a physical
system and they're able to then take the
knowledge of the gain and say things
about how frequently someone may speak
in a conversation how frequently other
people may interrupt what the
composition is of different people
speaking so if there are five people in
a group maybe three of the people are
speaking eighty percent of the time and
the other two people hardly speak at all
looking at those kinds of relationships
that are embedded in the behavior of the
people themselves and then from the
mathematical relationships between the
data they gather the
able to discover really interesting
things about how the social systems work
and then they can introduce new
management frameworks information
architectures creative design processes
or in the case of say a city where there
might be a disease that's spreading from
person to person to try to stop the
spread of the disease by using real-time
data to tell people using visual
representations of the data of the data
flow where they should go that their
least likely to become infected by the
disease and this is a way for people
just like how we use traffic congestion
data now using something like Google
Maps to tell us that we should take the
bridge that goes over the water instead
of taking the overpass that goes down
through downtown because we'll avoid
traffic in exactly the same way people
can use real-time data to figure out how
to avoid becoming part of an epidemic
which means that public health officials
could stop an epidemic in its tracks so
this is the kind of thing of the book
explores and if you're a social
scientist or a marketer or an urban
planner or a campaigner who wants to
spread ideas increase creativity and
innovation in your organization make
your city or your society safer or
healthier the next book provides an
excellent overview of the future of
social science so that's it that's all
I'll say for now I recommend you go
ahead and get the book yourself and
again it's social physics biology
bendlin enjoy